<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-13T13:06:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rachel M Fisher</title><subtitle>Hello, I&apos;m Rachel. I joined The Catholic Church at Pentecost 2021 after about 2 years of prayer and research. I am so excited to share my thoughts on faith and Catholic things with all of you.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Christmas Reflections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachel's%20reflections/2022/01/03/christmas-reflections.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas Reflections" /><published>2022-01-03T18:11:39-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-03T18:11:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachel&apos;s%20reflections/2022/01/03/christmas-reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachel&apos;s%20reflections/2022/01/03/christmas-reflections.html">&lt;p&gt;It may seem strange to have a Christmas reflections post come after Christmas, but in the Catholic Church, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucatholic.com/blog/when-does-christmas-actually-end/&quot;&gt;Christmas liturgical season&lt;/a&gt; goes from Christmas Day until the Baptism of the Lord (Jan 9th this year). And historically, Christmastide didn’t end until February 2nd at The Presentation of the Lord, also known as Candlemas. You might be thinking “Wow, that’s a really long time! I don’t want to keep celebrating the Christmas season all the way up until February!” And I hear you, but we live in the era of holiday creep and our culture starts Christmas celebrations rather early by historical standards. Traditionally, the start of the Christmas celebration was much closer to Christmas and not all the way in November. So really, I am posting about Christmas during Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, onto my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmas morning my husband and I went to Mass at our local parish. During Mass, I love to fix my eyes on the crucifix during the liturgy. That particular Sunday, as I was looking at the crucifix and thinking about the nativity scene, the subject of the day’s gospel readings, it occurred to me that before he was even born, Jesus chose to suffer on our behalf. Now, this wasn’t really a brand new thought. I’d been aware of it before. Of course, Jesus choose to be born and to die on the cross. But I don’t know that the gravity of that had really sunk in before. The profound nature of what that means about his love for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, sitting in the pew, thinking about how Jesus, the second person of the Trinity, existing with the Father before the beginning of time itself, voluntarily chose to humble himself and take on human flesh. Now, before we ever get to the matter of his torture and death let’s just reflect for a moment about what he choose for himself. He choose to take on the regular sufferings that come with human existence: pain, hunger, exhaustion, cold, heat, and let’s not forget temptation to sin. Wow. But of course, we know he doesn’t stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does he choose to become human, but he chooses to become human so that he can suffer torture and die horrifically on a cross. He chooses to suffer for our benefit. Now, I’m sure all parents can relate to being willing to suffer on behalf of their children. But if you had the choice and the power of God would you willingly suffer or would you arrange things in a way that would spare you from suffering? I would. Who wants to suffer if they don’t have to? And that’s the thing. Jesus didn’t have to. He chose to. More freely than any of us choose our suffering because he did have the power to end his own suffering at any point he wanted to. And yet, out of complete obedience and love for us, he didn’t. This is so profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this may sound more like a Good Friday reflection rather than a Christmas reflection but I don’t think they are mutually exclusive. For, as the Catechism of the Catholic Church (CCC) states, ” ‘All that Jesus did and taught, from the beginning until the day when he was taken up to heaven,’ is to be seen in the light of the mysteries of Christmas and Easter.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:a&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:a&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And there certainly isn’t an Easter without a Good Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I love reflecting on the crucifix. It reminds me what love is. That love, genuine love, is willing to suffer on another’s behalf. And Jesus was willing to suffer so much out of love for us. How many times have I not wanted to do something for another person simply because it would cause me the extremely mild suffering of an inconvenience? Too many times to count. Reflecting on Christ’s incarnation and suffering helps me curb that selfishness. When I feel that selfishness creep up I ask myself, “Am I loving this person like Jesus would want me to?” And if I’m honest with myself, the answer is probably “no” and I need to do a course correction so that “I don’t really feel like it” becomes “I’ll do that out of love.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of us may be called to endure suffering similar to Christ’s through martyrdom. All of us, however, are called to endure the small sufferings of everyday life out of love for our fellow humans. Things like filling up the Brita pitcher even though I don’t feel like it. Putting that shopping cart where it belongs. Picking up my trash I just dropped in the parking lot. Christ was willing to suffer tremendously to reconcile the human race to God. Am I willing to suffer even in the smallest way to show love to those around me? I’m working on that answer always being yes but I’m not quite there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:a&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Catholic Church. 2000. Catechism of the Catholic Church. 2nd Ed. Washington, DC: United States Catholic Conference. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:a&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Rachel&apos;s Reflections" /><category term="Christmas" /><category term="suffering" /><summary type="html">It may seem strange to have a Christmas reflections post come after Christmas, but in the Catholic Church, the Christmas liturgical season goes from Christmas Day until the Baptism of the Lord (Jan 9th this year). And historically, Christmastide didn’t end until February 2nd at The Presentation of the Lord, also known as Candlemas. You might be thinking “Wow, that’s a really long time! I don’t want to keep celebrating the Christmas season all the way up until February!” And I hear you, but we live in the era of holiday creep and our culture starts Christmas celebrations rather early by historical standards. Traditionally, the start of the Christmas celebration was much closer to Christmas and not all the way in November. So really, I am posting about Christmas during Christmas!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Be Not Afraid</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachel's%20reflections/2021/12/31/be-not-afraid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Not Afraid" /><published>2021-12-31T18:11:39-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-31T18:11:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachel&apos;s%20reflections/2021/12/31/be-not-afraid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachel&apos;s%20reflections/2021/12/31/be-not-afraid.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to share something I wrote in my journal after a Lectio Divina session a few months ago. Lectio Divina is a way of prayerfully reading a short passage of scripture, reflecting on it, and allowing God to speak to you through it. I’m sharing this not because I think I have some great insight but in the hopes it might help someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-passage&quot;&gt;The Passage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark 9:30–37 (RSVCE)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 They went on from there and passed through Galilee. And he would not have anyone know it 31for he was teaching his disciples, saying to them, “The Son of man will be delivered into the hands of men, and they will kill him; and when he is killed, after three days he will rise.” 32But they did not understand the saying, and they were afraid to ask him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reflecting on this passage, the phrase that stood out most to me was “they were afraid to ask him.” The more I reflected on this the more I realized that the reason it stood out to me is that I too have been afraid of asking him. What follows is my journal entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-journal-entry&quot;&gt;The Journal Entry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am often afraid. My husband once said I operate out of a place of fear. He isn’t wrong. Anxiety is often my default reaction to any changing situation, the suggestion of changing situation, or an unknown situation. This also affects my relationship with God. I am often afraid to listen to what he might want me to do because I am afraid it might be something that makes me uncomfortable. I imagine the most uncomfortable situations. I catastrophize even what I think God might call me to do even though he’s never called me to do anything that hasn’t been of my benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just always afraid of the worst-case scenario even when it hasn’t happened. I need to learn to trust in God. I know intellectually that he wants what is best for me and listening to him is always to my benefit. I need to internalize that knowledge and live it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard and I know I can’t do it alone. But I am not alone. I need to write down the times I’ve followed God and the benefits that came of it. I should also write down the times I had anxiety and didn’t trust but God was faithful and my anxiety was unfounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reflection&quot;&gt;Further Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I think about this passage and what I wrote, the more it occurs to me that my anxiety might also be a way of knowing what earthly things I’m too attached to. What am I afraid of losing by doing whatever God may ask of me. My house? My comfort? My pets? My job? My spouse? My family? And yes, all those things have occurred to me at one point or another. As I said, I can really go down a rabbit hole of worst-case-scenario thinking. But let’s for a moment think that the worst-case in my brain happens? What then? Well, it would result in some suffering on my part. It would be hard. But is there any level of suffering that God can’t reward with even greater joy? No, there isn’t. God can either reward those who follow him in this life if he chooses but most certainly will in the next life. And isn’t that, as Christians, where our focus is supposed to be? Everything in this world is fleeting and will pass away. For as John said in his Apocalypse:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3and I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling of God is with men. He will dwell with them, and they shall be his people, and God himself will be with them; 4he will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning nor crying nor pain any more, for the former things have passed away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revelation 21:3-4 (RSVCE)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what have I to fear after all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not claim that now I am suddenly over this anxiety. I’m not. There’s a vast difference between me understanding intellectually that I need not fear and me living that out. I’m a work in progress and aren’t we all. Thank God that he sent his Holy Spirit to work in us and it isn’t all up to us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Rachel&apos;s Reflections" /><summary type="html">I want to share something I wrote in my journal after a Lectio Divina session a few months ago. Lectio Divina is a way of prayerfully reading a short passage of scripture, reflecting on it, and allowing God to speak to you through it. I’m sharing this not because I think I have some great insight but in the hopes it might help someone else.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I’m Starting this Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachel's%20reflections/2021/06/03/why-im-starting-this-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I’m Starting this Blog" /><published>2021-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachel&apos;s%20reflections/2021/06/03/why-im-starting-this-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachel&apos;s%20reflections/2021/06/03/why-im-starting-this-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to blog for over a decade now. I’ve had a few incredibly short-lived blogging attempts before, but never stuck with it. Mainly because I’m a perfectionist-procrastinator who could never seem to come up with the perfect blogging niche that I felt compelled or interested in writing about frequently. I’d have an idea for a blog, write a post, then come up with another idea I thought was better. I never gained traction on anything because “what if I had a better idea” paralyzed me from moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got back into my faith when God called me to join the Catholic Church. Ever since then, I have wanted to share my experience learning and living the Catholic faith. I felt God calling me to write. Like I had finally found the topic he wanted me to write on. Then, of course, I put it off. For over a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I put it off? Because my tendency towards perfectionist-procrastination reared its ugly head. Truth is, I was afraid. Perfectionism is frequently born out of fear: fear of failure and fear of success. Who was I to start writing about faith? I don’t have a theology degree. My field of study is in biology and history (and certainly not church history). I work in IT. So why on earth did I think I was qualified to speak about faith? What if I got something wrong? What if I wrote stuff that no one cared about? What if my efforts just went flat. On the other hand, what if my writing was successful? What if I built up an audience? Then I’d have an obligation to that audience. What if I let them down? Also, what if God wasn’t really calling me to do this but it was just my own ego wanting to be important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list goes on. Basically, I was letting my own anxiety and perfectionism get in the way of doing what I believe God called me to do. At least, what I think God is calling me to do. And if he is calling me to do this, then all I need to do is give it my all and let him take care of the rest. It doesn’t have to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reminded of Moses who didn’t want to be God’s spokesperson to Pharaoh. He had all kinds of excuses. Like me. God used him anyway. God can use any of us. We just have to be willing to show up and let him work through us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My verse going forward for this blog is Matthew 10:19 (RSCVE): “When they deliver you up, do not be anxious how you are to speak or what you are to say; for what you are to say will be given to you in that hour; for it is not you who speak, but the Spirit of your Father speaking through you.” This is what Jesus told the Apostles to prepare them for their ministry and persecution. I find it a good reminder that God often gives us what we need when we need it and not before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>User</name></author><category term="Rachel&apos;s Reflections" /><category term="welcome" /><summary type="html">I have been wanting to blog for over a decade now. I’ve had a few incredibly short-lived blogging attempts before, but never stuck with it. Mainly because I’m a perfectionist-procrastinator who could never seem to come up with the perfect blogging niche that I felt compelled or interested in writing about frequently. I’d have an idea for a blog, write a post, then come up with another idea I thought was better. I never gained traction on anything because “what if I had a better idea” paralyzed me from moving forward.</summary></entry></feed>